Talha Bin Saeed

Karachi Division, Pakistan



talhabinsaeed@yahoo.com



+923122626021



linkedin.com/in/talha-bin-saeed-54637799

Summary

Searching for a position that will allow me to improve my current programming, problem solving and communication skills by acting as a steppingstone into the industry. Looking forward to a long and mutually beneficial relationship and teamwork.

Possessing a great interest in Networking, Mobile and Desktop Platforms, Software Development and Administrative assistance in Information Technology while specially in Web-development using MERN stack. Being well-acquainted with Microsoft Azure, Microsoft SQL Server, Visual force and Lightning Salesforce CRM, PaaS and SaaS platforms along with data analysis, leadership skills and flexible attitude enables me to provide the most of outcomes while applying engineering concepts in day to day operations to troubleshoot even in stressful environment.

Being familiar with Trello, Jira, Git, Ms Project, Confluence and MS Visio makes me an experienced Systems Analyst, and are transferable skills for a Program Management, Operations Management and Product Management role to implement budgeting and process improvement.

My portfolio can be found at https://tbs.netlify.app/

- Trailhead Ranger https://trailblazer.me/id/tsaeed
- Successfully completed AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator certification course.
- Successfully completed The complete Web Developer 2021: Zero to Mastery.
- Successfully completed 40 hours of CBAP Certified Business Analysis Professional exam preparation
- Successfully completed Google Project Management: Professional Certificate

Experience

Visiting Lecturer

Bahria University Karachi Campus

Mar 2022 - Present (1 month +)

Visiting Lecturer for Web Engineering.

Visiting Lecturer for Engineering Management.

N

System Analyst

Neusol LLC

Oct 2016 - Present (5 years 6 months +)

- · Creating workflow for e-services.
- Creating Software Requirements Specification for various projects.
- · Requirements gathering
- · Liaising with other IT staff such as programmers to produce new systems
- Producing specifications for new or modified systems

Salesforce Developer Intern

Dale Carnegie Australia

Feb 2020 - Apr 2020 (3 months)

- Creating Reports and Dashboards using SaaS Salesforce to perform Data Analysis.
- Keeping track of the performance of the Sales team using PaaS Salesforce.
- Responsible for creating process manuals which provide guidelines for configuring and troubleshooting the Salesforce environment along with some networking knowledge.

Ľ滤 Masters Student

University of Technology Sydney

Feb 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 10 months)

Worked on multiple Web development and salesforce related projects.

Major responsibilities for Web development projects:

- · Website development.
- Implementation of responsiveness.
- · DOM manipulation.
- Implementation of APIs.
- Working on top of bootstrap templates.
- Implementation of MailChimp.
- Using React, Node.js + Express.js , PostgreSQL for web development.

Major responsibilities for salesforce projects:

- Responsible for implementing data objects.
- Responsible for implementing validation rules.
- Responsible for implementing Organisation-wide defaults.
- Responsible for implementing role hierarchy.
- Responsible for implementing email notifications.
- Responsible for implementing task creation and assignments.
- Responsible for implementing time-based workflows.
- Responsible for creating a written report for the prototype.

Achievements:

Prototype completion with distinction.

Junior Web Developer

Web Developers Academy

Jun 2016 - Jan 2017 (8 months)

- · Creating front-end and back-end of various websites using PHP.
- Creating websites using WordPress.
- Implementing responsiveness in websites.
- Developing database using Navicat Premium and Microsoft SQL.

bex. Customer Service Representative

ibex. Pakistan

Jan 2016 - Jun 2016 (6 months)

- Process claims and provide IT Service Management for a USA based company Square Trade's clients using salesforce.
- Perform as a technical escalation point for the frontline team.

- Maintain customer satisfaction for Ibex Global clients by providing periodic after hours assistance based on the roster.
- Perform data entry, ticketing and process work-order line items for the clients using Salesforce via phone support.
- Provide customer feedback to Technical Lead and assist Quality Assurance Team.

Notnet Developer Intern

Neusol LLC

Jun 2015 - Aug 2015 (3 months)

- Responsible for working on Asp.net and advanced Telerik UI tools.
- Develop the survey generator keeping the future requirements in mind like adding more languages by using the language plugin.

Education



University of Technology Sydney

Master of Engineering - MEng, Software Systems Engineering Major Mar 2017 - Nov 2018

ECA Professional Year Program

ECA Professional Year Program, ECA Professional Year Program, Computer Software Engineering
Jun 2019 - May 2020

🗱 University of Technology Sydney

Master of Engineering Management, Software Systems Engineering Major Mar 2017 - Nov 2018

Bahria University

Bachelor of Software Engineering (B.S.E.), Computer Software Engineering Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Licenses & Certifications

Dale Carnegie Immersion Course - Dale Carnegie Australia

103 Trailhead Badges and 61,525 Trailhead Points - Trailhead by Salesforce

AZ-104 Microsoft Azure Administrator Exam Certification 2021 - Udemy UC-f7252d27-678b-4ad2-923b-8b1a6d744110

Challenge Explorer (1 hands-on lab completed)

- 40 Contact Hours of Business Analysis Education IIBA Pakistan Chapter PRUDSOL-BA-1221
- Google Project Management: Professional Certificate Coursera | Google e226bab6460acb0837f9040bcb68360f

Skills

Web Development • Salesforce.com Development • Android Development • User Interface Design • PHP • JavaScript • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • React.js • Project Management